# KANISHK ANAND

- (a) kanishk.kanishk.anand@g mail.com
- h 997 101 0807
- a Gurgaon, Haryana 121001

https://www.linkedin.com/in/kanishk-anand-b86b07121

https://kanishkanand.github.io/portfolio/

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Prolific, full stack web developer with a passion for metrics and beating former "best-yets." Delivered more than 25 projects meeting highest web development standards, with optimal performance benchmarks. Decreased rework by 22% and infrastructure costs by 50%. Consistently receive high user experience scores for all web development projects, including a 100/100 on Lighthouse Audit. Passionate about building world class web applications.

#### **SKILLS**

- Javascript, ES6, React JS, R edux JS, Node.JS, jQuery
- CSS, SCSS, Emotion, Bootstr ap
- NGINX
- HTML
- Bundlers: Webpack, Rollup
- AWS: EB, Elasticache, EC2
- Web Performance
- Web Security
- Agile workflow processes

### **EDUCATION**

Shiv Nadar University Greater Noida, UP • 05/2018

**Bachelor of Technology**: Computer Science

- Graduated with 9.26 GPA
- Awarded certificate of Highest Distinction
- Majored in Computer Science and Engineering
- Member of Project Samuday, HCL

The Asian School Dehradun, UK • 03/2014

#### Senior Secondary School

- Graduated with 94.2%
- Member of Quiz Society, Debate Society, Football
- Awarded Governor's Award
  (Highest Merit Award) from 2006 - 2014
- Received numerous laurels from Chief Minister, Governor of Uttarakhand, and other renowned personnels

#### WORK HISTORY

### OYO Rooms - Senior Frontend Developer 01/2020 - Current

- Part of consumer experience platform team, designing architecture and developing reusable modules and libraries for entire team.
- Developed an inbuilt library to replace moment (date management library) for performance. The inbuilt library is 2KB compared to moment's 60KB (gzip).
- Introduced critical CSS for OYO Rooms' website, leading to a boost in performance metrics, which further saw 30% reduction in bounce rate.
- Responsible for driving performance and security optimization across the consumer website.

## OYO Rooms - Frontend Developer 05/2018 - 01/2020

- Part of consumer facing team, and responsible for converting business proposals to technology driven features.
- Responsible for designing and delivering the architecture of OYO Rooms Microsite, using React decorators to partner with other companies with minimal engineering bandwidth, which now drives ~50% of OYO website revenue.
- Responsible of revamping URL routing using NGINX reducing latencies per URL.
- Driving performance optimizations on the website, improving TTI, FCP, leading to 20% more user retention.
- Responsible of revamping UI/UX of entire user journey flow on Desktop and Mobile Web, which led to 40% revenue increase.
- Revamped OYO Rooms' mobile website offline user experience using service worker.
- Redesigend users' session persistance leading to 70% reduction in infrastructure cost.

### ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Improved website's performance and latency leading to Lighthouse Audit score of 100/100 on all metrics.
- Invited to attend international conferences: Google I/O 2019, Google Chrome Dev Summit 2019, Google Perf Workshop 2019.
- Member of the team designing and developing OYO Lite,
  a TWA based mobile app (~800 KBs of size )
- Won 2nd Runners' up in OYO Rooms' Tech Conference for SimpleLogin Project, that improved user login on OYO Rooms website and app.